<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esphome :: Digital Dilemma</title>
    <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/index.html</link>
    <description>This is a new chapter.&#xA;ESP Project Boxes Measuring Voltage With an Esp32 Measuring Wind With Esphome One Wire</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:26:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Voltage With an Esp32</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-voltage-with-an-esp32/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:26:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-voltage-with-an-esp32/index.html</guid>
      <description>A fun little project that has a useful function for me – wirelessly connecting a vehicle battery to Home Assistant.&#xA;Justification: I wanted to be able to check my vehicle’s battery was good, and automatically alert me if it wasn’t.&#xA;I own a classic Land Rover that doesn’t get driven enough, and I wanted to keep an eye on the battery voltage so that I knew when to put it on charge, using HA to alert me when it dropped below a certain point. That worked well for a while, but then I had much worse problems with my Motorbike which, despite two new batteries, went low enough to fail to start after only 10 days. I spent a long time trying to sort out the parasitic drain, but the general advice was “They all do that”. So I got a Optimate battery tender that trickle-charges it. The only problem was remembering to plug the thing in! So I moved my widget across to the bike shed and connected it directly to the 12v feed on the tender. Now, if I forget to plug it back in and the voltage drops below 12.6v, I get a SMS telling me I’ve been forgetful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Wind With Esphome</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-wind-with-esphome/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:18:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-wind-with-esphome/index.html</guid>
      <description>One very windy Autumn night, I wondered just how hard was the wind blowing? Spotting a cheap anenometer on Ebay, I figured it was worth trying to add this to my HA setup. It turned out to be surprisingly easy and in just an afternoon, things were up and working beautifully.&#xA;The WH1090 in-situ and working&#xA;The Physical Bits One Anenemeter, a HADEX WH1080. Although pretty much any pulse-based meter will work. It has two wires and putting a multimeter across them, I saw that one full revolution opens and closes these wires three times. Considering how fast these things can spin, that’s going to take a lot of counting! I extended the wiring by soldering and heat-shrinking a 5 meter length of bell wire onto it, then tested again. I mounted it on a shelf bracket with a suitable sized bolt that neatly screws into the mount, as i don’t have the full weather-station kit this unit comes with. This sits near my garage, although it’s not a great position since it’s quite sheltered. However, this is just a fun little project and I’m not too worried about its accuracy, and I won’t be sharing speeds with anyone else. One ESP8266 or ESP32 or similar chip. I’ve used a Nodemcu chip without any additional backboarding or hats. I put it in an old light-switch box just for some protection from knocks. Inside this scruffy thing lies the ESP8266, honest! Next time I’ll take better photos</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using One Wire sensors in ESPHome</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/one-wire/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 19:19:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/one-wire/index.html</guid>
      <description>Onewire / 1wire / one wire / Dallas / Maxim is a very cheap way to deploy single or multiple temperature sensors, plus some other devices such as mini wireless buttons.&#xA;I’ve been using them at my house for around twelve years with lots of success, first connecting them to Domoticz and later, Home Assistant. There’s several ways to use them and I’ll explain a couple.&#xA;One wire with Home Assistant (ESPHome and ESP32/ESP8266 controllers, or USB) This is my absolute favourite way of using these sensors nowadays. I find working with ESPHome a pleasure and the wiring is very simple and forgiving. There are various forms of connectors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containers for ESP Projects</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/esp-containers/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 19:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/esp-containers/index.html</guid>
      <description>A selection of random containers I&#39;ve used for Home Automation projects</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>