<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wind :: Category :: Digital Dilemma - Personal Tech, Projects and Software</title>
    <link>https://digdilem.org/categories/wind/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:18:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://digdilem.org/categories/wind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Wind With Esphome</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-wind-with-esphome/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:18:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-wind-with-esphome/index.html</guid>
      <description>One very windy Autumn night, I wondered just how hard was the wind blowing? Spotting a cheap anenometer on Ebay, I figured it was worth trying to add this to my HA setup. It turned out to be surprisingly easy and in just an afternoon, things were up and working beautifully.&#xA;The WH1090 in-situ and working&#xA;The Physical Bits One Anenemeter, a HADEX WH1080. Although pretty much any pulse-based meter will work. It has two wires and putting a multimeter across them, I saw that one full revolution opens and closes these wires three times. Considering how fast these things can spin, that’s going to take a lot of counting! I extended the wiring by soldering and heat-shrinking a 5 meter length of bell wire onto it, then tested again. I mounted it on a shelf bracket with a suitable sized bolt that neatly screws into the mount, as i don’t have the full weather-station kit this unit comes with. This sits near my garage, although it’s not a great position since it’s quite sheltered. However, this is just a fun little project and I’m not too worried about its accuracy, and I won’t be sharing speeds with anyone else. One ESP8266 or ESP32 or similar chip. I’ve used a Nodemcu chip without any additional backboarding or hats. I put it in an old light-switch box just for some protection from knocks. Inside this scruffy thing lies the ESP8266, honest! Next time I’ll take better photos</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>