<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project :: Category :: Digital Dilemma - Personal Tech, Projects and Software</title>
    <link>https://digdilem.org/categories/project/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:44:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://digdilem.org/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redneck PC Water Cooling</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/misc/redneck-water-cooling/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/misc/redneck-water-cooling/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cooling servers using household plumbing&#xA;“How to water cool computers using household plumbing equipment”&#xA;I like peace and quiet. Most water cooling rigs available for home PCs are anything but – they only use water to move the heat away from the CPU and GPU to a finned radiator, then blast it with fans. I thought that radiant cooling would work and not need any fans, so I built a water cooling system. It worked perfectly for a linux server and my gaming windows PC for three years, until I had to free up space and instead focussed on sound proofing a cupboard and using air cooling. This was back in 2010 but there’s no reason why it wouldn’t work today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tall People and Series Land Rovers</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/land-rover/tall-people-and-series-land-rovers/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:38:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/land-rover/tall-people-and-series-land-rovers/index.html</guid>
      <description>One problem taller people often have in old Land Rovers is they can be really uncomfortable to drive. I’m 6’2″ and with the standard seats, I would start to get bad cramp in my ankle and legs after only 15 minutes or so. The adjustment in the seat is very limited because of the cross bulkhead immediately behind the seat.&#xA;There is a relatively simple modification which gives you an inch or two extra space that doesn’t seem to be widely used, however, and is cheap and quick to do. It’s also fully reversible!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Voltage With an Esp32</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-voltage-with-an-esp32/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 15:26:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/esphome/measuring-voltage-with-an-esp32/index.html</guid>
      <description>A fun little project that has a useful function for me – wirelessly connecting a vehicle battery to Home Assistant.&#xA;Justification: I wanted to be able to check my vehicle’s battery was good, and automatically alert me if it wasn’t.&#xA;I own a classic Land Rover that doesn’t get driven enough, and I wanted to keep an eye on the battery voltage so that I knew when to put it on charge, using HA to alert me when it dropped below a certain point. That worked well for a while, but then I had much worse problems with my Motorbike which, despite two new batteries, went low enough to fail to start after only 10 days. I spent a long time trying to sort out the parasitic drain, but the general advice was “They all do that”. So I got a Optimate battery tender that trickle-charges it. The only problem was remembering to plug the thing in! So I moved my widget across to the bike shed and connected it directly to the 12v feed on the tender. Now, if I forget to plug it back in and the voltage drops below 12.6v, I get a SMS telling me I’ve been forgetful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Zigbee Sensors Running in Extreme Cold</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/zigbee-sensors-in-the-cold/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 21:08:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/home-automation/zigbee-sensors-in-the-cold/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Aqara (and other) Zigbee devices are great in almost every situation. But when using them in cold conditions, such as inside a freezer, the default CR2032 batteries don’t last well, especially in subzero temperatures.&#xA;Fortunately, it’s really simple to adapt them to use the much larger and commonly available 18650 Lithium rechargable batteries. I’ve had several of these batteries reporting the temperature of my freezer in around -20c for over a year without needing recharging – quite remarkable!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitting gas rams to a Land Rover’s Bonnet</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/land-rover/fitting-gas-rams/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 18:12:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/land-rover/fitting-gas-rams/index.html</guid>
      <description>Easier access!&#xA;The standard Series Land Rover bonnet has no gas or spring assist, instead using a tethered prop. Replacing it with some gas rams makes it a lot easier to lift and also allows it to lift further and higher out of the way.&#xA;Front view&#xA;The fitting is fairly simple – in this case I’ve used two fairly low powered rams (from the tailgate of a Toyota Yaris). These are mounted to a single plate fixed to the bulkhead, and onto a metal plate bolted onto one of the main ribs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Himalayan: Fitting a 16t Sprocket</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-16t-sprocket/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:45:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-16t-sprocket/index.html</guid>
      <description>A 16t sprocket suitable for Himalayan and Scram motorbikes&#xA;The Reasoning One of the most popular modifications for the Royal Enfield Himalayan is to replace the front drive sprocket which changes the gearing through all gears.&#xA;The stock Himalayan is fitted with a 15-tooth (15t) front sprocket which takes drive from the engine onto the chain. This provides reasonable gearing for the 24.5bhp for a wide variety of riding surfaces, but as the bike only has five gears, this means that top-end speed is undergeared, and to achieve motorway/highway speeds you must push the engine into the 5k to 6k range (70mph indicated = 5800rpm for my tests on stock tyres, level road). As the engine redlines at a low 6000 this means a lot of noise, vibration and engine wear to keep up with traffic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Ammo Boxes to my Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-ammo-boxes-to-himalayan/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:57:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-ammo-boxes-to-himalayan/index.html</guid>
      <description>Who wants to pay £500 for the official panniers? Not me!&#xA;Perhaps not to everyone’s taste, but ammo boxes are cheap, strong and last forever. They’re easy to fit, too!&#xA;Backstory I like to carry a few things when I’m riding. Tools, a can of tyre weld, a spare litre of fuel, a couple of cereal bars and, being English, a flask of tea. So luggage was always something I needed. However, the official RE Panniers are surprisingly expensive, so originally I fitted two £10 military surplus kit bags like so:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>