<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modifications I’ve made to my Himalayan :: Digital Dilemma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/vehicles/motorbikes/himalayan-modifications/index.html</link>
    <description>Helping me find nice places&#xA;After 5,000 miles and the Himalayan is pretty much perfect for me. Where they weren’t, I made some tweaks to suit me.&#xA;A 16 tooth front sprocket - £16 This took half an hour to fit. Changing from the original 15t sprocket means that all the five gears are somewhat taller, but this allows for a much nicer on-road experience I’ve found Pros: Better economy, lower revs and vibration at motorway speeds. (RPM at 70mph drops around 600 from around 5200 to 4600) Cons: Higher first gear. Can be a stretch to fit on a new chain. Recommended? Yes, for all users except those who ride a lot of technical off road stretches where the lower 1st gear is most useful. Those riders may even consider a 14t. Clip-on screen protector - £20 A small generic clip-on screen extender. I tried the Puig screen but hated it, and the clip-on reduces buffeting enough for my 6’2″ lump. Fuelx Lite - £150 The factory tuning for all modern motorbikes is very lean to meet emissions. Devices like the FuelX sit between the oxygen sensor and the ECU and change the signals to trick the ECU into delivering more fuel. Pros: Engine runs cooler and has a stronger “pick-up” in revs, especially at the lower end. It’s easily fitted and also easy to remove. (The Pro version has handlebar buttons to change maps, which require more fitment. I went with the Lite) Cons: Slightly lowered economy. Recommended? Yes. I didn’t have high expectations of this, but I did immediately feel and hear the difference. It’s a small gain - maybe 1 or 2hp, but worth the relatively modest price, I think. Rear Pannier Frame - £50 Necessary to fit saddlebags or panniers. There are many available, but fall into two camps: Official Royal Enfield, or Copy. I bought a Copy from an Indian seller on Ebay, all of whom seem to be selling the same item. Pros: Easy to fit. Cons: Terrible quality! Initially the welds looked poor, and the metal thing. Within a year, one lower strut snapped off, having rusted through from the inside. I inspected the other and found it was also about to fail, then replaced both with some flat metal I had. After that, I lost an entire 50cal Ammo can pannier complete with all contents (Tools, spares etc) somewhere on the road one day. The top weld had snapped entirely. I spent a few hours making better mounts out of angle iron - these definitely aren’t going to fail! Recommended? No! The RE official item is probably better, but stick to branded pannier mounts. Sidestand plate - £5 Just a little plate that bolts onto the sidestand. This keeps the bike slightly more upright, but widens the footprint to stop the bike sinking on soft ground. Happy with this. Oxford Heated Grips - £60 I ride year-round and England is not a tropical country. I consider these essential on any motorbike ridden here in the grey six months of winter.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/vehicles/motorbikes/himalayan-modifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>