<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motorbikes :: Digital Dilemma</title>
    <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/index.html</link>
    <description>A late biker, I love exploring Devon and its surrounds on my 2023 Royal Enfield Himalayan&#xA;Himalayan St Davidstowe</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 18:08:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Honest) Review of Puig Touring Windscreen for the Royal Enfield Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/review-puig-windscreen/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 18:08:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/review-puig-windscreen/index.html</guid>
      <description>I bought it but I put the original back after only one ride…&#xA;The stock 2023 Himalayan is a great bike, but head and body wind protection is pretty minimal. Having come from a BMW R1200GS with an amazing Givi Airflow screen, I missed being able to ride with an open helmet at everything other than motorway speeds, so went shopping.&#xA;The only really affordable option I found was the Puig Touring screen, available Clear, tinted or smoked. So I paid £110 to the cheapest decent ebay supplier and bought it. It turned up a few days later, not very well packaged but was undamaged and still in original packaging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selling My Dream Motorbike</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/selling-dream-motorbike/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:54:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/selling-dream-motorbike/index.html</guid>
      <description>The TV Program, Long Way Round was what made me want a motorbike, and specifically a BMW GS. In my mid 40s and facing a mid life crisis, I decided to do bikes. I wanted to travel the world too. It looked cool, it looked fun, it looked interesting.&#xA;So I did my CBT (Uk basic test), bought a £300 Chinese 125 and rode through the winter to get some miles in. Then booked the DAS test (same as the EU bike test – it’s tough) and then went to a bike showroom and ended up buying a high-mileage 2004 BMW R1200GS with full luggage – even before I passed my test. Luckily I did pass and loved riding it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Himalayan: Fitting a 16t Sprocket</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-16t-sprocket/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:45:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-16t-sprocket/index.html</guid>
      <description>A 16t sprocket suitable for Himalayan and Scram motorbikes&#xA;The Reasoning One of the most popular modifications for the Royal Enfield Himalayan is to replace the front drive sprocket which changes the gearing through all gears.&#xA;The stock Himalayan is fitted with a 15-tooth (15t) front sprocket which takes drive from the engine onto the chain. This provides reasonable gearing for the 24.5bhp for a wide variety of riding surfaces, but as the bike only has five gears, this means that top-end speed is undergeared, and to achieve motorway/highway speeds you must push the engine into the 5k to 6k range (70mph indicated = 5800rpm for my tests on stock tyres, level road). As the engine redlines at a low 6000 this means a lot of noise, vibration and engine wear to keep up with traffic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Honest) Review of Oxford Heated grips for the Royal Enfield Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/honest-review-oxford-grips/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:32:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/honest-review-oxford-grips/index.html</guid>
      <description>Grips fitted. Note oxford control box on left&#xA;I’m a huge fan of heated grips, having discovered them on my GS. When I was learning to ride a bike, I rode through the winter on a Sinnis Cafe 125 and often got so cold I’d have to pull over and warm my hands on the engine – sometimes every 2 or 3 miles. My circulation isn’t the best thanks to beta blockers, and that also means I get vibration numbness fairly quickly when it’s cold – so I pretty much consider grips a necessity for riding in the UK 3/4 of the year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Ammo Boxes to my Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-ammo-boxes-to-himalayan/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 14:57:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/fitting-ammo-boxes-to-himalayan/index.html</guid>
      <description>Who wants to pay £500 for the official panniers? Not me!&#xA;Perhaps not to everyone’s taste, but ammo boxes are cheap, strong and last forever. They’re easy to fit, too!&#xA;Backstory I like to carry a few things when I’m riding. Tools, a can of tyre weld, a spare litre of fuel, a couple of cereal bars and, being English, a flask of tea. So luggage was always something I needed. However, the official RE Panniers are surprisingly expensive, so originally I fitted two £10 military surplus kit bags like so:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving a Himalayan Seat</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/improving-a-himalayan-seat/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 13:24:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/improving-a-himalayan-seat/index.html</guid>
      <description>I love my Himalayan, but the seat is not its best feature. It’s hard, strangely narrow and angles forwards. Not only giving you a numb and then increasingly painful rear end after a time riding, but also squishing your gentleman’s equipment against the fuel tank.&#xA;My first attempt to fix this was the buy the genuine Royal Enfield “Touring seat” for £70.80. It’s an easy swap – just remove the old and slip in the new. But, amazingly, I couldn’t tell the difference! It felt exactly the same. It wasn’t made the same; it was open underneath and there was a different mesh where it was solid in the other, but it was just as hard and uncomfortable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Villaging With the Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/villaging-with-the-himalayan/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:46:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/villaging-with-the-himalayan/index.html</guid>
      <description>I like to ride for pleasure at least once a week, but have been getting a bit bored with riding the same roads and lanes. I’m fortunate to have some beautiful countryside nearby (Dartmoor – I’m in England) but even so, it’s a bit repetitive eventually.&#xA;My solution to this ‘problem’ is to set myself a target – to take my Himalayan to every Village in my home county of Devon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modifications I’ve made to my Himalayan</title>
      <link>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/himalayan-modifications/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 10:41:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://digdilem.org/vehicles/motorbikes/himalayan-modifications/index.html</guid>
      <description>Helping me find nice places&#xA;After 5,000 miles and the Himalayan is pretty much perfect for me. Where they weren’t, I made some tweaks to suit me.&#xA;A 16 tooth front sprocket - £16 This took half an hour to fit. Changing from the original 15t sprocket means that all the five gears are somewhat taller, but this allows for a much nicer on-road experience I’ve found Pros: Better economy, lower revs and vibration at motorway speeds. (RPM at 70mph drops around 600 from around 5200 to 4600) Cons: Higher first gear. Can be a stretch to fit on a new chain. Recommended? Yes, for all users except those who ride a lot of technical off road stretches where the lower 1st gear is most useful. Those riders may even consider a 14t. Clip-on screen protector - £20 A small generic clip-on screen extender. I tried the Puig screen but hated it, and the clip-on reduces buffeting enough for my 6’2″ lump. Fuelx Lite - £150 The factory tuning for all modern motorbikes is very lean to meet emissions. Devices like the FuelX sit between the oxygen sensor and the ECU and change the signals to trick the ECU into delivering more fuel. Pros: Engine runs cooler and has a stronger “pick-up” in revs, especially at the lower end. It’s easily fitted and also easy to remove. (The Pro version has handlebar buttons to change maps, which require more fitment. I went with the Lite) Cons: Slightly lowered economy. Recommended? Yes. I didn’t have high expectations of this, but I did immediately feel and hear the difference. It’s a small gain - maybe 1 or 2hp, but worth the relatively modest price, I think. Rear Pannier Frame - £50 Necessary to fit saddlebags or panniers. There are many available, but fall into two camps: Official Royal Enfield, or Copy. I bought a Copy from an Indian seller on Ebay, all of whom seem to be selling the same item. Pros: Easy to fit. Cons: Terrible quality! Initially the welds looked poor, and the metal thing. Within a year, one lower strut snapped off, having rusted through from the inside. I inspected the other and found it was also about to fail, then replaced both with some flat metal I had. After that, I lost an entire 50cal Ammo can pannier complete with all contents (Tools, spares etc) somewhere on the road one day. The top weld had snapped entirely. I spent a few hours making better mounts out of angle iron - these definitely aren’t going to fail! Recommended? No! The RE official item is probably better, but stick to branded pannier mounts. Sidestand plate - £5 Just a little plate that bolts onto the sidestand. This keeps the bike slightly more upright, but widens the footprint to stop the bike sinking on soft ground. Happy with this. Oxford Heated Grips - £60 I ride year-round and England is not a tropical country. I consider these essential on any motorbike ridden here in the grey six months of winter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>